# Kristian Smith

# Junior Full Stack Developer

#### **Contact**

Sköntorpsvägen 115,12053, Årsta, Sweden (+46) 763 55 96 32 <u>kristiansmith@me.com</u> GitHub - KristianDsmith Linkedin – <u>Kristian Smith</u> Resume – <u>Kristian Smith</u>

#### **Education**

April 2023-October 2023

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development Code Institute - Dublin, Ireland

September 2004-May 2005

Sound Engineering and Production Ladbroke Grove Studios, City University, London

September 2003-May 2004

Music Business / Marketing and Law City University, London

#### Technical skills

HTML5 -technologies CSS3 - technologies JavaScript - technologies Python - technologies React - framework jQueery - framework Bootstrap - framework Django - framework MongoDB - database MySQL - database Github - version control

### **Executive Summary**

As a Junior Software Developer with a Full Stack Software Development Diploma graduating October 2023 from Code Institute, I excel in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Python. With two decades of experience in Restaurant and Hospitality, I am a skilled team player with strong communication and creative problem-solving abilities. I have successfully led teams in agile environments, including start-ups, across various locations.

My diverse skill set includes restaurant management, operations, marketing, supply chain, and project management. Eager to transition into the tech industry, I seek an opportunity to join an exciting development team, fostering personal growth and making a meaningful impact.

# Portfolio of projects

Kristian Smith – Interactive resume website for presentation.

Technologies/Framework – HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQueery.

Git Hub - <a href="https://kristiandsmith.github.io/Kristian-Smith-resume-2023/">https://kristiandsmith.github.io/Kristian-Smith-resume-2023/</a>

Street Gastronomy – Brand website for a Jamaican cookbook called Roots. Technologies uses – HTML5, CSS, JavaScript. Git Hub - https://kristiandsmith.github.io/streetgastronomy/

Battleship Game – A simple designed user vs computer battleship game. Technologies Used - Python Heroku - https://battleships-23-b994430075a8.herokuapp.com/

Tic Tac Toe Game – A simple designed two player Tic Tac Toe Game. Technologies Used - HTML5, CSS with JavaScript. GitHub - <a href="https://kristiandsmith.github.io/tic-tac-toe-project2/">https://kristiandsmith.github.io/tic-tac-toe-project2/</a>

Wave - brand website for a an Eco Surf and Yoga Retreat in Portugal. Technologies Used - HTML5, CSS.

GitHub - <a href="https://kristiandsmith.github.io/wave-project-1-official/">https://kristiandsmith.github.io/wave-project-1-official/</a>

#### Professional skills

Organisational
Agile Methods
Time Management
Creativity
Growth Mindset
Project Management
Problem solving
Development
Management
Customer Service
Communication
Adaptability
Operations

#### Personal

Music & Production Food & Wine Travelling & Exploring Outdoors Active sports Meditation Healthy lifestyle

#### Certification

Udemy - HTML5, CSS3 Udemy - JavaScript Udemy - Python Udemy - React NVQ Level 3 Food Production NVQ Level 1 & 2 Catering & Hospitality

#### Languages

English - Mother tounge Swedish - Basic

# **Experience**

March 2020 – April 2023

Creative Director • Director • Curb Food

- Developed and launched successful food tech start-up, Curb Food.
- Implemented Agile approach to establish 15 innovative restaurant concepts across Sweden, Germany, and Denmark.
- Optimised kitchen design through data analysis, resulting in enhanced operational efficiency.
- Established robust foundations for streamlined kitchen operations across all locations.
- Pioneered supply chain network setup and product development in collaboration with Curb suppliers.
- Utilised data-driven approach to develop and enhance culinary concepts and dishes.

*July 2019 – March 2020* 

Restaurant Consultant • Consultant • Krstian Smith Gastronomy

- Established and oversee the street gastronomy sector within the company.
- Offered expertise and direction to enhance 5 restaurants by implementing menu engineering, supply chain management, inventory planning, and safety protocols.
- Curated engaging recipe content for social media platforms, resulting in obtaining an Ambassadorship.

November 2019 – March 2020

Head Chef • Manager • Hobo Hotel

 Innovated and introduced the highly successful restaurant concept, Hobo XO.

March 2015 – June 2019

Lead Culinary Creative • Manager • Jay Dub Productions

March 2012 – June 2015 Chef • Flippin Burgers

June 2011 – March 2012 Paternity leave

April 2009 – May 2011

E-commerce Manager • Manager • Time W&J design AB

- Successfully developed and delivered e-commerce and brand websites to enhance online presence and user experience.
- Implemented impactful SEO marketing strategies to drive increased visitor traffic and boost sales.

#### References

Carl Tegberg Curb Food Founder, CEO